# Olivia (Liv) Riggins

# **Associate Technical Writer**

riggins.liv@gmail.com | 507-301-4965 | Stanford, CA | linkedin.com/in/liv-riggins

Portfolio: https://liv-riggins.github.io/portfolio/

# Summary

Associate technical writer with experience in technical writing, editing, UX/usability research, and audio production. I thrive in environments where I can work towards creative, user-centered solutions while using my strengths as a highly organized, methodical thinker.

### **Certifications and Skills**

- Salesforce Certified Administrator (July 2021-Present)
- Madcap Advanced Developer (March 2021-Present)
- HTML/CSS
- Github
- Professional Communication
- Project Management
- Jira/Confluence
- Java
- Adobe Creative Suite
- Adobe Framemaker

# **Experience**

## Associate Technical Writer, Veeva Systems

July 2020-Present

Work in an agile, rapid release environment to:

- Research and write online help articles for business users, developers, end users and administrators
- Create engaging video walkthroughs and tutorials for new features
- Take ownership of documentation for multiple features, embedded in cross-functional teams
- Invest in CRM by becoming a product expert and keeping up with new features, including those documented by other writers
- Ensure new articles maintain a consistent style, tone, and approach by following a style guide, reviewing existing documentation, and participating in peer reviews

#### Technical Writer Intern, Graco Inc.

Jan. 2019-July 2020

Design, develop, and write technical materials for Graco products in accordance with corporate, engineering, and legal standards, working under a senior technical writer and with engineers, illustrators, and designers. Manage the quoting and award process for 30+ translation projects.

### Writing Consultant, University of Minnesota Center for Writing

Aug. 2018-June 2020

Work one-on-one with graduate and undergraduate students from a wide range of academic backgrounds, nationalities, and levels of writing proficiency to improve their academic and scientific writing. Develop user guides, instructional materials, and a Center for Writing style guide as special projects for writing center directors.

## **Education**

#### University of Minnesota, summa cum laude

B.S. Technical Communication, IT and Design focus

B.A. English

- Summa thesis in usability testing and UX redesign for online health software
- Minors in Interdisciplinary Design and Digital Media Studies
- Coakley Ames Writing Excellence Award recipient, University Honors student